Guide to the John Gunther Papers 1935-1967
University of Chicago Library
- Series XI: Inside Africa
  - Subseries 8: Correspondence-Post-publication
    - Nyasaland (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Portuguese Africa (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Rhodesia (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - The Sahara (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Dr. Albert Schweitzer (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Spanish Africa (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Sudan (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Tanganyika (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Tunisia (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Uganda (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Union of South Africa (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Zanzibar (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - General A-B (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - General C-G (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - General H-K (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - General L-P (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - General R-S (Box 76, Folder 28)
    - General T-Z (Box 76, Folder 29)
  - Subseries 9: Research Notes-Algeria
    - Interview notes, Paul Auriol Interview notes -Cochett Interview notes -Gauntlett (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Leclarire Interview notes -Miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 10: Research Notes-Basutoland
    - Interview notes, E. P. Arrowsmith (Resident Commissioner) Brian Marwick (Government Secretary) Dr. James Moroka (South Africa Nationalist Leader) Yeats and Norton Miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Notes on a trip through area (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outline (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 11: Research Notes-Bechuanaland
    - Interview notes, David Astor (journalist) T.C. Robertson Kenneth Thompson (Colonial attache) R. E. Turnbull (Secretary to High Commissioner) Gordon Walker (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 12: Research Notes-Belgian Congo
    - Interview notes, "Belgian Boys" (Officials in New York) Victor Brabant Colonel Cooke H. A. A. Cornelis (Director, 10 Year Plan) Serge Fliegers (journalist) George Greaves (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Interview notes, C. J. P. Ionides (Game hunter) Harold Isaac (journalist?) Aime Marthoz (Director, Union Miniere) Murdock George Padmore (journalist) Leon Petillon (Governor) Interview notes -Emory Ross (Missionary) (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes, Robert Scheyven (Ruanda-Urundi official) Monsigner Sigismundi (Apostolic Delegate) Kenneth Thompson Miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Union Miniere-Interview notes, David Lilienthal (Chairman, A. E. C.) Ridley Jean de Ryckman de Betz (Company official) Edgar Sengier (Company president) Joseph Volpe (U.S. lawyer) (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Union Miniere-Miscellaneous notes (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Notes on Leopoldville; Elizabethville; Kibangu-Kitawala (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Notes on Boende (Dr. Henry Horner, medical missionary) (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Names, outlines (Box 77, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 13: Research Notes-Cameroons
    - British, Interview notes-E. J. Gibbons (Commissioner) Interview notes-Kenneth Thompson Miscellaneous notes (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - French, Interview notes-Virginia Lubkin (American M.D.) Interview notes-Miscellaneous Miscellaneous notes (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Interview notes, Abdul Rahman Azzam (former Secretary-General, Arab League) Caffrey (U.S. Ambassador) M. Clark (journalist) (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Interview notes, Mahmound Fawzy (Foreign Minister) John Hamilton (British Embassy official) Robert MacClintlock (U.S. Ambassador) Abdel Khalek Massouna (Secretary-General, Arab League (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Interview notes, General Mohammed Naguib (former President) (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Interview notes, Pannaker Robert Payne (U.S.I.S., Cairo) (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Interview notes, Hussein Selim (Professor) (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Interview notes, Smart Sir Ralph Stevenson (British Ambassador) Weathersby Leigh White (journalist) (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Interview notes- Miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Notes on General Naguib (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Interview notes, R. Allen Col. Edward Hopkins, (Commander, Radio Marina,) U. S. Post) Loomis Tesemma Family John Wardle-Smith (British Consul General) (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 14: Research Notes-Ethiopia
    - Interview notes, A. H. Garretson (American advisor to Ethiopian Foreign Office) W. G. Golein (Head, Ethiopian, Air, Lines) Haile Selassie (Emperor) Nathan Marein (advisor to Emperor) (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Count C. G. von Rosen (Head, Air Force Training) "schoolteacher" Miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Notes on Emperor and Imperial family (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Notes on foreign advisors (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Addis Ababa; history, Moslems; religion; slavery; trip to Bishaftu (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outline (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 15: Research Notes-French Equitorial Africa
    - Interview notes, Mrs. Cloud Cockburn D. Latham Kenneth Thompson Roger Vaurs (Director, French Press Service, New York) Walter White (N.A.A.C.P. leader) Miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Notes on Brazzaville; trip from Brazzaville to Lambarene to Libreville (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes with Albert Schweitzer and notes on Lambarene (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 16: Research Notes-French West Africa
    - Miscellaneous notes, Dahomey Dakar (Federal Capital) Guinea Ivory Coast Mauretania Senegal Sudan Upper Volta (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 17: Research Notes-Gold Coast
    - Interview notes, Sir Charles Arden-Clarke (Governor) David Astor (London journalist) J. A. Braimah (Minister of Communications) C. Y. Carstairs (Colonial Office official) Michael Ensor (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Interview notes, Robert Fleming (Public Affairs Officer, U. S. Consulate) Kimla Agbeli Gbedemah (Minister of Finance) Joyce Gittens (Nkrumah's secretary) Lord Hemmingford Robert Jackson (Director, Volta Dam project) J. V. A. Lillie-Costello (Chief Information officer) (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Oliver Lyttleton (Colonial Secretary) R. J. Moxon (Gunther escort to Kumasi) (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, Kwame Nkrumah (Prime Minister) (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes, Sir Reginald Saloway (British official) Lloyd Shirer (Missionary, Tribal Chief, British official) Kenneth Thompson Richard Wright (author) Miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Ashanti-Interview notes, E. H. Adams (Resident architect, Kumasi Hospital) Samuel Arthur (Editor, Ashanti Pioneer) W. H. Beaton I. A. Beveridge (Conservator of Forests) K. N. Lucie-Smith (Asst. Director of Agriculture) Leslie Saich (Regional officer, Ministry of Labor) (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Ashanti-Interview notes and notes on Ashantihene (Tribal chief) (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Ashanti-Miscellaneous notes (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - Notes on Nkrumah (Box 78, Folder 23)
    - Notes on meeting of Parliament; tribal chiefs (Box 78, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 78, Folder 25)
    - Names, outlines (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 18: Research Notes-Kenya
    - Interview notes, Sir Evelyn Baring (Governor) Vernon Bartlett (Journalist) (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Michael Blundell (farmer, political leader) (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, Faubion Bowers (writer) Ralph Bunche (U.N. Official) J. H. Candler (District Officer) C. Y. Carstairs (Colonial Office official) F. N. Cavendish-Bentinck (British official) (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Sir Andrew Cohen (Governor of Uganda) Col. Mervyn Cowie (Director, National Parks) A. J. Friedgut (New York) A. H. Garretson (Addis Ababa) W. B. Havelock (farmer, political leader) Hawkins (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, General Hinde E. F. Hitchcock (Tanganyika) Henry Howard (Governor's secretary) Kesick Wolfgang Langewiesche (writer) David Mathew (Roman Catholic Archbishop) E. W. Mathu (Kikuyu leader, legislator) (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, George Padmore (writer) Lady Portsmouth Sir Robert Scott (East Africa High Commission) Interview notes -E. A. Vasey (British official) Eric Sherbrooke Walker (Treetope) Richard Webb (British Information Service) John Wordsworth (District Officer) (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes- Miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Kikuyus, Mau Mau, Kenyatta (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Nairobi; Indians; Legislative Council and politics (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Names, outlines (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 19: Research Notes-Liberia
    - Interview notes, A. Albert J. D. Clark (UNESCO) R. De Sales (U. N. Information Center) Vernon Mckay (State Department official) Miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Notes on President Tubman (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Notes on Firestone Company; Technical cooperation Administration (Point 4) (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 20: Research Notes-Libya
    - Interview notes, Dr. Arneizi Leo Cyr (State Department official) Colonel Johns (archaeologist) George Littledale (Point 4 official) (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, B. More Colonel Shaw Henry Villard (U.S. Minister) Miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Notes on King Idris (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Notes on Italians; British; Americans (USIS, Point 4, Wheelus A. F. Base) (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Notes on Libyan Leaders; prime minister (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - Notes on Tripoli; Fezzan; Sabratha; Cyrenaica; Benghazi (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous notes; outlines (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 21: Research Notes-Madagascar
    - Interview notes, Michael de Camaret (French Foreign Ministry Official) Harris Kenneth Thompson Roger Vaurs Miscellaneous notes (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 22: Research Notes-Morocco
    - Interview notes, Abdel Krim (Moorish chieftain, Rif region) Abdullah Paul B. Mme. de Blesson Mme. Boniface Col. J. Q. Braddock (U.S. Air Force) Cortes Pierre David-Weill Geoffroy De La Tour du Pin (Councilor to Sultan) (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, John Dorman (U.S. Consul, Rabat) (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, El Glaoui (Pasha of Marrakesh) (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, George Greaves (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, General Augustin Guillaume (Resident-General) (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, Brigadier General W. H. Hardy (U.S. Air Force) Hassan General d'Hauteville (French commander, Marrakesh) Hayne Miss Howe Jay Lewis Jones Lamont (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes, Pierre Lyautey (nephew of Marshal Lyautey) (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Interview notes, Hubert McMickey Mme. Parlange Pender (U.S. businessman, Coca Cola Co.) (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Interview notes, Si Sadek (son of El Glaoui) (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Interview notes, F. Southworth Van Latham Roger Vaur Vincent (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes, Miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Notes on Casablanca; Fez; Marrakesh; Port Lyautey; Rabat; trip to Telouet-Ouarzazate-Tinerhir-Ksar es-Souk (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Notes on U.S. Air Bases; Nationalists; Berbers (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Notes on the Sultan; the French; El Glaouri (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 23: Research Notes-Nigeria
    - Interview notes, Abdullah Bayero (Emir of Kano) Adeniji Adela II (Oba of Lagos) S. L. Akintola (former govt. minister, politician) Obafimi Awolowo (politician) Barrett (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Brown Gordon Butler (Public Health Officer, Kankiya) C. Y. Carstairs T. W. Chalmers (Director, Nigerian Broadcasting) (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, B. E. B. Fagg (government archaeologist) Gunning (government official) H. U. Kaine (Lawyer, Lagos Town Council) Sir Hugo Marshall (Lieutenant Governor) (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes, Miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - Notes on Lagos; Eastern Nigeria, Dr. Nanamdi ("Zik") Azikiwe (with clippings about Gunther from "Zik's" newspaper); Western Nigeria and Obafimi Awolowo (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - Notes of Northern Nigeria-Kano; Katsina, Jos (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - Notes on the North-The Sardauna of Sokoto, the Shehu of Bornu; general (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - Notes on politics (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - Names, outlines (Box 80, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 24: Research Notes-Northern Rhodesia
    - Interview notes, C. Y. Carstairs (Colonial Office Official) J. Desmond Clark (Rhodes-Livingston Museum) C. G. R. Clay (Provincial Commissioner) Phillip Court (M. D., British Medical Officer) Sir Stuart Gore-Brown (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, H. H. Hochschild (American Metal Co., Copper belt) Phillips Sir Gilbert Rennie (Governor) Sir Ellis Robins (Resident Director, British South Africa Co.) (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, F. M. Thomas Roy Welenski (political leader) Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Notes on Lusaka and Nddo; Copper Belt and mining (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outline (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 25: Research Notes-Nyasaland
    - Interview notes, Malcolm Barrow (Executive Council) C. Y. Carstairs (Colonial Office) W. A. W. Clark Rev. Andrew Doig (Legislative Council) William Rangeley (Provincial Commissioner) Abdul Satar Sacranie (Lawyer) Dr. Michael Scott Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 26: Research Notes-Portuguese Africa
    - Interview notes, William Rangeley (Nyasaland) Emory Ross (missionary) G. M. Teixeria (Governor-General, Mozambique) Elmer Yelton (U.S. Consul General, Luanda, Angola) Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Schools; Lourenco Marques, Beira; immigrants, South Africans, Indians; assimilados (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Mozambique-Miscellaneous notes (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Angola-Miscellaneous notes (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - São Tomé-Miscellaneous notes (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 27: Research Notes-Ruanda-Urundi
    - Interview notes, A. Claeys-Bouüaret (Governor) Mwami of Ruanda (king) Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Notes on trip to Ruanda-Urundi; pygmies and Watutsi (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 28: Research Notes-Sahara
    - Interview notes, Claude Blanquernon (Schoolmaster, Tamanrasset) L. Cabot Briggs (U.S. Anthropologist, Algiers) (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Erickson (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, Captain Lecointre (Chief administrator, Hoggar) Father Lusson (Pere Blanc) (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes, Jean Pierre Sartin (French captain) Captain Thomas (Oilman, In Salah) Roger Vaurs (French Information Services, New York) Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Notes on trip across desert; Tamansrasset, In Salah, El Goléa, Tauregs (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous notes, outlines (Box 81, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 29: Research Notes-Sierra Leone
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - Interview notes, Ralph Bunche (U. N. official) Harris (Nairobi) W. Smith Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 30: Research Notes-Southern Rhodesia
    - Interview notes, William E. Arnold (Public Relations Dept.) Colin Black (High Commissioner's Office, London) Chief Justice Charles D. Converse (U.S. agronomist) H. A. Cripwell (Native Dept.) Everard (General manager, Rhodesia R. R.) Greenfield (Box 81, Folder 24)
    - Interview notes, Sir Godfrey Huggins (Prime Minister, Central African Federation) Negro Boy C. M. Newman (Mayor, Bulawayo) Shri Apa B. Pant (High Commissioner to East Africa) Paver (African journalist) Lord Salisbury (Box 81, Folder 25)
    - Interview notes, David Stirling (President, Capricorn Africa Society) Gordon T. Thornycroft Miss Treadgold Richard Webb (British Information Office, New York) Irene Worth (London) Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 26)
    - Notes on Salisbury, Bulawayo; Rhode's grave (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Notes on color bar, Indians, immigration, voting, government; industry, agriculture, mining (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Notes on history; education; visit to native reserve (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Notes on Central African Federation (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 31: Research Notes-Sudan
    - Interview notes, R. Allen Abdul Azzam (former Secretary-General, Arab League) M. Bell Colonel Wareford [?] Brown Daniel M. H. Evans (Press Officer, Khartoum) (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes, Howe (Governor-General) Latif W. H. T. Luce (Provincial Governor) Robert MacClintlock (U.S. Ambassador, Egypt) Davis T. Myall (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Interview notes, Yacob Osman (Umma politician) Sir James Robertson (Civil Secretary) Sar (El Sayed Sir Abdul Rahman el Madhi Pasha) General R. D. Scoones (Commandant of army) Sitwell (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Interview notes, Mrs. Sloan Speake Sir Ralph Stevenson (British Ambassador to Egypt) Sweeney Miscellaneous (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Notes on politics, SAM, SAR, Khalifa, Khartoum, Omdurman; trip down Nile; trip to Gezirah; public celebration (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 32: Research Notes-Swaziland
    - Interview notes, Brian Marwick (Government secretary) Sobhuza II (Paramount Chief) Stokes R. E. Turnbull (Secretary to High Commissioner) Miscellaneous Miscellaneous notes; names (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 33: Research Notes-Tangiers
    - Interview notes, José Archer (Administrator) William Bird (U.S. representative on International Commission) Leo Cyr (State Department official) Fritz Southworth Miscellaneous (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous notes, outline (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 34: Research Notes-Tanganyika
    - Interview notes, C. Y. Carstairs (Colonial Office Official) Sir Eldred Hitchcock (President, Sisal Growers) G. R. A. M. Johnston (White settler) Thomas Marealle (Chagga Paramount Chief) David Mathew (Roman Catholic Archbishop) (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Interview notes, Sir Edward Twining (Governor) (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, J. T. Williamson (diamond industrialist) Miscellaneous (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Notes on diamond mining (H. E. Burgess, J. T. Williamson) (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - Notes on Masai and Chagga tribes; Arabs, Indians, Moslems, whites; Mt. Kilimanjaro (Box 82, Folder 19)
    - Notes on agriculture (ground nuts, sisal, coffee); Colonial Development Corporation (Box 82, Folder 20)
    - Notes on Paul von Lettow-Vorbeck and German rule (Box 82, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 82, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 35: Research Notes-Tetuan
    - Interview notes, Pierre Graham (U. S. Legation) George Greaves Langenheim McCann Jaime Menendez Ralph F. Southworth Miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous notes; outline (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 36: Research Notes-Togoland
    - Interview notes, Michael Ensor Sylvanus Olympio (Nationalist Leader) Kenneth Thompson (Colonial attaché) Miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 37: Research Notes-Tunisia
    - Interview notes, Salah Eddine Ben Mohammed Bacchouche (Prime Minister) de Boississon (Deputy to High Commissioner) L. Cabot Briggs (U.S. Anthropologist, Algiers) Leo Cyr (State Department official) Gibbs Lewis Jones (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, Le Breton Hedi Nouira (Nationalist leader) Sheriff (Tourist Bureau) Roger Vaurs (French Press Service, New York) Miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Farhat Hached and nationalist movement; the Bey and his family; Kairouan and other cities (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 38: Research Notes-Uganda
    - Interview notes, J. P. Birch (Resident, Buganda) C. Y. Carstairs (Colonial Office official) Cobb (King's College teacher) (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Interview notes, Sir Andrew Cohen (Governor) (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes, T. R. F. Cox (Provincial Commissioner) De Busen (Principal, Makerere College) Gordon Gore A. J. Kerr (Register of Cooperative Societies) S. W. Kulubya (Unofficial member, Executive and Legislative Councils) (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes, A. N. Maini (Mayor, Kampala) David Matthew (Roman Catholic Archbishop, Kenya) I. K. Musazi (Uganda National Congress leader) Miss Pelham (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Interview notes, J. T. Simpson (Unofficial member, Executive Council) (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes, Horace White (Public Relations Officer) Miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Notes on Kabaka; Owen Falls dam; Jinja; Entebbe-Kishwamba; customs duties; social affairs; trip through countryside (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous notes; names, outlines (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 39: Research Notes-Union of South Africa
    - Interview notes, H. M. Basner (Lawyer) Peter Bridges William Brown Ralph Bunche (United Nations Official) Alec Campbell (on Southwest Africa) Sir Christopher Chancellor (Reuters official) Cowan (on Cecil Rhodes) (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, Dr. Y. M. Dadoo (President, South African Indian Congress) (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes, T. E. Donges (Minister of the Interior) (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Interview notes, P. Duncan (Opposition leader, son of former Governor-General) I. D. Du Plessis (Ministry of Interior official) Edmunds (on diamond mining) W. W. M. Eiselen (Secretary for Native Affairs) Harry Ellis (Editor, Nuaualu) (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Interview notes, A. J. Friedgut (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Interview notes, Dr. Friedman Bryon Frisbie (Minerals attache) Gallman (Pretoria) Manilal Ghandi (Son of the Mahatma) George J. Golding (President, Colored People's National Union) Mrs. Good G. C. Grant (Principal, Adams College) (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Interview notes, Charles Hlengwa (Chief, Numandara Tribe) H. K. Hochschild (American Metal Company, Rhodesia) Mrs. Hoernle (former anthropology professor) Father Trevor Huddleston (Anglican priest, missionary) Jooste Journalists (Box 83, Folder 23)
    - Interview notes, Sam Kahn (Communist member of Parliament) H. V. Kaltenborn (Radio commentator) Olga Levison (Box 83, Folder 24)
    - Interview notes, Julius Lewin (Professor of Native Law, University of Witwatersand) (Box 83, Folder 25)
    - Interview notes, Sir Percival Liesching (High Commissioner) Eric Louw (Minister of External Affairs and Finances) Albert Luthuli (Zulu chieftain) (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Daniel Malan (former Prime Minister) E. A. Malga (journalist) Lt. Col. B. W. Martin (Pietermaritzburg) Hymie Miller (Mayor, Johannesburg)Folder (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, A. I. Minty (lawyer) John Neser (Chief Government Secretary, South West Africa) Henry Nxumalo (African Drum) Sir Ernest, Harry Oppenheimer (Anglo American Corp., De Beers Consolidated Mines, Ltd.) (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Alan Paton (author) Oswald Pirow (former Minister of Defense) Eleanor Ponsonby "Pretoria Man" T. C. Robertson (Editor, the Veldtrust) (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, Rosenthal Ross Erwin Schuller South African Ambassador to United States Colin Stamp (United Party leader) J. G. N. Strauss (United Party leader) (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, J. G. Strijdom (Prime Minister) (Box 84, Folder 6)